# **ELIAS MEDINA**

LA PLATA · BUENOS AIRES, ARGENTINA · +54 221-5258-394 · ELIASMEDINA86@GMAIL.COM

I'm a Quality Assurance professional with 9+ years of experience in the field. I been involved in all kind of testing projects with some of the biggest names in the industry such as Electronic Arts, Tribune, Bioware and Deloitte among others.

I have work experience in the fields of Game Testing, Mobile Testing, Web Testing and Automated Testing. I'm always up for a challenge, the more technical the better. I have a broad technical set of skills that helps me a great deal to face complex tasks, and even gives me the opportunity to create tools and solutions that would help junior testers to perform their tasks in better ways.

I do love to share what I learn and had been coaching junior QC and QA analyst for years to help them grow in their careers. I'm currently working as a Senior QC Lead for complex tax projects for Globant and Deloitte companies.

# **EXPERIENCE**

SR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + DELOITTE

I'm working as a QC and QA lead analyst. Providing quality assurance and quality control processes for key projects and new web applications under active development. I'm also leading an automation initiative using WebdriverIO with JS and Node to automate core features of the applications under development. This lets me mix my technical skills with my task-force leading skills to face a highly demanding work load.

August 2016 - Present

SSR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + TRIBUNE PUBLISHING (NOW TRONC)

Worked on MDM implementation, a data management project in which we needed to sanitize all Tribune customer data from duplicates and outdated records while providing Tribune enterprise systems with a new data management framework. This was a very tough project and required a lot of research and presented very complex technical challenges.

December 2014 - August 2016

# SSR OC LEAD

GLOBANT + TRIBUNE PUBLISHING (NOW TRONC)

I Worked as QC Lead with Tribune Company's development team located in Los Angeles and Chicago. Where I planned, performed and monitored, QA and QC tasks and processes over several systems which were all consumed from a single mobile app. I've also performed automated testing on the mobile app and helped debugging and improving the framework.

March 2014 - December 2014

# SSR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + SCHELL GAMES + AMPLIFY

I worked on an educative project for Schell Games and Amplify. This time taking care of the Quality processes performed on iOS devices as well as providing UI/UX feedback, aiming to create a really good usage experience of the products being developed while assuring the overall quality and functionality of the specified requirements.

August 2013 - February 2014

#### SSR QC LEAD

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS

I worked as QC Lead on the release of one of the biggest multiplatform football games on the market, FIFA 14 project. My role in this project was to take care of the QA/QC validations for the Kinect & Move technologies as well as the overall stability of the title on all supported platforms. Another huge project with very serious deadlines to work with.

March 2013 - August 2013

# OC LEAD ANALYST

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS

I worked with EA again, this time with Montreal, Vancouver and Redwood Shores offices. I was tasked with testing and improving EA Origin client for Mac. I had a small test team of 10 employees and we verified and validated a huge software catalog to ensure they work well with Origin for Mac. (More than 200+ Titles between games and other software).

October 2012 - March 2013

# QC LEAD ANALYST

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS CANADA

I took the role of test lead of the Globant QA Test Team, this time working for EA Los Angeles, performing QA processes for the EA multiplatform title: Medal Of Honor Warfighter.

March 2012 - October 2012

#### OC ANALYST

GLOBANT + ELECTRONIC ARTS

I started working as a game tester for EA's FIFA franchise. Later I was assigned as POC (point of contact) of everything online related about the FIFA franchise and had to work closely with EA's Leads to coordinate testing efforts and communicate quality reports.

March 2011 - April 2012

# **QA ANALYST**

MOZILLA AURORA NETWORK

I took part of a collaborative testing initiative for Mozilla's FireFox browser. My tasks involved testing the new builds released on the Mozilla Aurora Channel under different

versions of Operative Systems to ensure new versions will continue to work correctly on the OSs. Bug Reporting, analysis and testing of new requirements were also part of the job.

February 2010 - August 2010

# **EDUCATION**

# E-LEARNING PLATFORMS TO STAY IT RELEVANT!

QUALITY ASSURANCE AND PROGRAMMING

Proud student of world top's e-learning sites

Udemy, Udacity, Team Tree House, Acamica, Pluralsight, Microsoft Academy

Present

#### NATIONAL UNIVERSITY OF LA PLATA

COMPUTER SCIENCE DEGREE

Computer Science Track

2003 - 2008

# TECHNICAL EDUCATION SCHOOL N°1 EET

BACHELOR DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & PROGRAMMING

August 2002 - May 2006

### **SKILLS**

QUALITY ASSURANCE, PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

- Test Tracking Tools (Jira, TFS, Bugzilla)
- Functional Testing
- Regression Testing
- Cross Browser Testing & Debugging

- Compatibility Testing
- Automated Web Testing
- Agile Development & Scrum methodology
- Quality Assurance and Quality Control coaching
- Test Planning & Risk Assessment
- JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS
- NodeJS and NPM
- WordPress, React
- Selenium, Webdriver, WebdriverIO